# 嗨喽大家好
Hi guys
# 今天我伯爷去卖肉 剩了一个
Today my uncle went selling pork and there left a…
# 不是剩噶 留噶
Not left, you saved this one, huh?
# 专门给你留的
Just for you
# 留了一笼这个肥肠
A basket of intestines
# 所以我在想这个肥肠平时我们炒啊烧啊
Usually we stir fry it or sauté it
# 已经吃得有点腻了
And we got a bit tired of those
# 然后今天做一个肥肠鱼
So we’ll make a fish with pork intestine today
# 我把这个油啊这些把它撕完了要得不
Let’s rip off the fat from the intestine
# 还是要有点油 没得油在上面不好吃
Leave some fat on, otherwise it’s too dry
# 我们这个肥肠我以前做过实验的
I did experiments on the intestines before
# 反正这十斤肥肠处理得干干净净的出来的话只有三斤半
If you clean it really well, you get 3 pounds and a half out of 10 pounds
# 抓住它就把它撕掉了
You nip it and rip it off like this
# 肥肠鱼这个菜特别香
The dish is really savory and delicious
# 煮出来的话比单纯的水煮鱼要香
More savory than the mere hot chili oil fish
# 但是处理这个肥肠是很麻烦的
But it’s really a hassle
# 有好多都喜欢吃这个东西
Lots of people like pork intestines
# 吃这个东西就是麻烦得很
It just takes lots of time
# 现在我们这个肥肠直接倒到里面加一大把盐
Now we pour the intestines here and season with salt
# 然后再倒一点这个白醋
Then some white vinegar
# 陈醋也可以
The brown vinegar can do it too
# 但是陈醋有那个颜色
Despite the color
# 先给它来初洗几遍
First we wash it a few times
# 我们直接先把这个肥肠抓到非常粘手
Until the intestines feel very sticky
# 把它的那个黏液抓出来
That’s the mucus coming out
# 然后再用大量的清水把它清洗干净
Then use a lot of water to clean it
# 多洗几遍这个大肠
Wash it for a few more times
# 好 我们开始腌这个肥肠
Alright, let’s marinate the intestines
# 先倒点白酒
Some baijiu
# 然后还是再放点盐
Then some salt again
# 少一点这次就
A little bit less this time
# 然后我们倒一点这个小苏打
Then some baking soda
# 大约倒个10多克吧
About 10 grams or so (half an ounce)
# 然后给它抓一下
Then mix it well
# 加小苏打进去的话就是为了破坏这个肥肠的肌纤维
The soda is to break the intestine muscle fibers
# 让它可以在短时间可以把它煮熟 煮来咬得动
To make it cooked in less time and has a soft texture
# 如果你们喜欢吃一点都没有油的肥肠
If you prefer lean intestines
# 用完小苏打抓完之后再来撕这个油
Season with baking soda and then rip the fat off
# 可以把油撕得干干净净的 一点都可以不用留下
Then we can rip the fat completely off
# 你这个油不要撕干净很了 留点在上面
Leave some on
# 不是不好吃 没得油气得
Otherwise there’s no creamy taste
# 是不哦
Right?
# 是啊
Yeah
# 要得
Alright then
# 过于撕干净很了还有点朦朦 有啥子吃头呢
Too lean makes it dry
# 好 那我们这个就不撕那么干净
Alright then we’ll leave some fat on
# 就这样吧 现在我去杀鱼
This should be good. Now let’s prepare the fish
# 让它腌一会儿
Marinate the intestines for a while
# 热了点吃这个吃起你害不害怕上火哦
Isn’t the weather a little bit warm for the dish?
# 哎呀 反正上火的（食材）少整点在里头 这天气大了
Make it less spicy for the weather then
# 这点鱼片硬是拿给你片得好
The fish is filleted so well
# 一般
It’s okay
# 好了 我们这个肥肠就煮好了
Alright now the intestines are cooked
# 煮好了之后
After it’s done
# 因为我们加了小苏打
Because the soda in it
# 现在我们这个肥肠用手都可以掐得穿 你看
We can poke it through with our fingers
# 然后我们把剩下的这个肥肠斩成小块
We cut the intestines to little pieces
# 好
Like this
# 诶呀 好多哦
It’s a lot
# 下面我们就可以直接煮鱼了
Now we can cook the fish
# 锅中加入适量的菜籽油
Canola oil in the wok
# 少倒点诶
Hey, not that much
# 安
Okay
# 倒好多油哦
That’s so much oil
# 不得多
It’s okay
# 油温5成热之后加入切好的姜蒜泡椒末
Bring the oil to about 150 degrees C(300 F) and add the chopped green onions, ginger and pickled chili
# 再加入红油豆瓣酱炒香炒出红油
Then some chili oil doubanjiang and stir fry the red chili oil out
# 然后将切好的火锅底料下锅炒香炒化
Add the sliced hot pot soup base and stir fry
# 底料炒香之后加入腌制好的鱼骨头
After the aroma comes out, add the marinated fish bones
# 鱼骨头炒香之后加入适量的清水
Stir fry the fish bones and add some water
# 然后将准备好的配菜下锅
Then add the other ingredients
# 锅中加入食用盐2勺
Two spoons of salt
# 鸡精2勺
Two spoons of chicken bouillon powder
# 白糖1小勺
One spoon of sugar
# 适量的胡椒粉
Some pepper
# 配菜煮好之后捞出倒入盆中垫底备用
Boil the ingredients and lay them on the bottom of the bowl
# 然后将处理好的肥肠下锅
Intestines in the wok
# 将腌制好的鱼片依次下入锅中
Then the marinated fish fillets
# 将煮熟的肥肠和鱼片捞出倒入盆中
Boil the intestines and fish, then get them out in the bowl
# 再把烧开得汤汁倒入盆中
Bring the sauce to boil and pour in the bowl
# 下一步开始泼油
Then let’s splash oil on the dish
# 锅中加入适量的菜籽油
Canola oil in the wok
# 油温4成热之后加入青花椒和姜蒜末
Bring it to about 120 degrees Celsius (250 F) and add the green peppercorn, ginger and garlic
# 然后将爆香的配料均匀的泼在鱼片上面
Then splash the oil evenly on the fish
# 撒点葱花就可以吃了
Splash some green onions and it’s ready
# 好 可以了
Alright
# 四伯爷 尝哈看
Uncle, have a try
# 告哈看嘛
Come on
# 看好不好吃
Have a taste
# 你吃肥肠嘛
Do you like intestines?
# 我吃肥肠 我喜欢吃这个
Yes, I do
# 嗯 好吃
It’s good
# 入不入味
Is the taste inside?
# 入了味的
Yes it is
# 伯娘
Auntie
# 好吃 我不敢吃肥肠
Smells good but I don’t eat intestines
# 我吃块鱼
Let me have a piece of fish
# 这个没斩断 连起滴滴儿的
This one wasn’t cut
# 嗯 这个鱼好嫩哦
The fish has such a juicy texture
# 跟我上次做的差不多撒
Like the one I made last time
# 这个还好干（吃）点
This one is even better
# 还好吃点
Yeah it’s a little better
# 是不哦
Serious?
# 嗯
Yeah
# 这回做的好吃点啊
Better this time
# 这回做的还比头回好干
I can have more this time
# 上一次我跟我四伯做了一次水煮鱼片
I made my uncle some red chili oil fish last time
# 水煮鱼
Red chili oil fish
# 因为上一次没有加肥肠
And we didn’t have intestines the last time
# 这一次加肥肠煮完了之后这个汤特别香
The soup is extra delicious this time with the intestines
# 安逸 好吃
Nice! Delicious!
# 来得到火 这个菜
This dish is nice
# 肥肠鱼
Fish with pork intestines
# 嗯
Right
# 头次的没有加肥肠的嘛
We missed the intestines last time
# 嗯
Yeah
# 现在这个鱼才安逸哟我给你说
This dish is the one. So nice
# 嘿嘿 多吃点撒
Haha, have some more
# 这个鱼是最安逸的吃起
So nice!
# 肥肠你都咬得动啊
Can you chew the intestines?
# 咬得动
Yeah
# 是啊 咋个整的哦
How did you cook it so well?
# 咋个整的
The trick is
# 加了那个小苏打
the baking soda
# 哦
Oh
# 如果没有小苏打的话可以加点食用碱
If you don’t have baking soda around, use the soda ash
# 好了 本期视频就先到这里
Alright, that’s it for this episode
# 我还有几个菜要炒
I need to make a few other dishes
# 你去炒你的嘛 我干我的
You go ahead. I eat my own
# 诶呀 我尽（全部）干
Aha I can finish the dish
# 我等一哈（吃）
I’ll wait a second on that